Ying-I Lin (林瑛怡 · Lauren)

Product UX Designer

Email: yingyi518@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://laurenlin-portfolio.webflow.io/

Location: Taipei, Taiwan (Relocation, remote available)

About

I am a Product Designer with 5 years of experience in UI/UX design and visual design. I have worked on diverse projects across logistics, cryptocurrency, and education, both in the B2B and B2C sectors. My passion lies in crafting appealing interfaces that prioritize usability and functionality. By applying human-centered design thinking, I ensure that every design decision caters to the needs and goals of end-users, resulting in intuitive and delightful experiences.

Experience

GoFreight

Product designer

Mar 2020 -Mar 2023

Taipei, Taiwan

Product Team

- Lead design of EC-Booking, from user flows, prototype, UI designs to hand-off and ongoing feedback to Quality Assurance.
- Improving existing features for 2B SaaS system GoFreight FMS, 2C -Customer tracking portal working collaboratively with internal engineer team. (Website and Android App)
- Conduct relevant qualitative and quantitative research to discover customer needs, including data metric monitoring (hotjar, data studio), surveys and remote usability testing across different projects.

Design Team

- · Contributing to a growing multi-brands design system
- · Design reviewing, providing valuable feedback to my colleagues
- Mapping out the user journey of different roles based on user interview findings, resulting in the development of user-centered design solutions.

HowDesign

Visual designer

May 2018 -Jan 2020

Taipei, Taiwan

- Kidcastle China: Lead design of client's online course and foreigner tutor recruiting system from concept to wireframe, prototype and hand-off to developers
- Cryptocurrency exchange platform: Lead design of client's website and system from concept to wireframe, prototype and hand-off to developers
- Ideate, prototype and crafted customized website design for brands and companies
- Cover multiple projects in both print and website including: brochures, banners, digital advertising and websites.

Skills

Design Process

UI Design • Wireframes • Mockup • UI Flows • A/B Testing & Experiment • Design System

Research

Usability Testing • User Interviews • Data Analysis • Competitive Analysis • Heuristic Evaluation

Visual Design

Digital advertising · Website Design

Programming

HTML • CSS • Javascript

Education

MA Communication Design: Graphic Design

Kingston University (United Kingdom)

2016 - 2017

BA French Language and Literature

Fu Jen Catholic University (Taiwan)

2011 - 2015

Personal

APO Design (一塊設計) - Co-writer

https://apodesign.tw/

Tools

Design

Figma • Miro • Adobe Creative Suite • Maze • Data Studio • Wordpress • Webflow • Squarespace

Language

Mandarin - Native speaker English - Fluent French - Intermediate